here's a way to make geometric sense of
the infinite sum of the alternating
powers of one-third start with a one by
one square of area one cut it into three
pieces and remove one of those now cut
the diagram into three pieces vertically
and use that to re-add one third of the
missing area using these triangular
pieces now we repeat the process on the
Central Square created by the first two
divisions we cut that square into three
pieces remove one third and re-add
one-third with triangular diagrams we
continue this process indefinitely each
time decomposing the Central Square
which has one-ninth area of the previous
large Square using this process Shades
the alternating sum of the powers of
one-third on the other hand we see that
the Shaded area represents exactly three
quarters of the entire Square therefore
the infinite sum of the powers of
negative one-third is equal to
three-fourths
[Music]